<?xml version="1.0"  ?><!DOCTYPE pmc-articleset PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD ARTICLE SET 2.0//EN" "https://dtd.nlm.nih.gov/ncbi/pmc/articleset/nlm-articleset-2.0.dtd"><pmc-articleset><article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" article-type="research-article" xml:lang="en" dtd-version="1.4"><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">J Gen Physiol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">J. Gen. Physiol</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">484</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">jgenphysiol</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>The Journal of General Physiology</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">0022-1295</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1540-7748</issn><publisher><publisher-name>The Rockefeller University Press</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC2228570</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC2228570.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">2228570</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">2228570</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">229195</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1085/jgp.74.5.595</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">80073945</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Articles</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Light-induced dephosphorylation of two proteins in frog rod outer segments: influence of cyclic nucleotides and calcium</article-title></title-group><pub-date pub-type="ppub"><day>1</day><month>11</month><year>1979</year></pub-date><volume>74</volume><issue>5</issue><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">160521</issue-id><fpage>595</fpage><lpage>613</lpage><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>01</day><month>05</month><year>1980</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>23</day><month>04</month><year>2008</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2019-11-04 14:56:15.670"><day>04</day><month>11</month><year>2019</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><license license-type="openaccess"><ali:license_ref specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbyncsalicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This article is distributed under the terms of an Attribution&#8211;Noncommercial&#8211;Share Alike&#8211;No Mirror Sites license for the first six months after the publication date (see <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://www.rupress.org/terms">http://www.rupress.org/terms</ext-link>). After six months it is available under a Creative Commons License (Attribution&#8211;Noncommercial&#8211;Share Alike 4.0 Unported license, as described at <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/</ext-link>).</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="jg745595.pdf"/><abstract><p>Two minor proteins of frog rod outer segments become phosphorylated when retinas are incubated in the dark with 32Pi. The proteins, designated component I (13,000 daltons) and component II (12,000 daltons), are dephosphorylated when retinas are illuminated. The dephosphorylation is reversible; the two proteins are rephosphorylated when illumination ceases. Each outer segment contains approximately 10(6( molecules of components I and II. These remain associated with both fragmented and intact outer segments but dissociate from the outer segment membranes under hypoosmotic conditions. The extent of the light- induced dephosphorylation increases with higher intensities of illumination and is maximal with continuous illumination which bleaches 5.0 x 10(5) rhodopsin molecules/outer segment per second. Light which bleaches 5.0 x 10(3) rhodopsin molecules/outer segment per second causes approximately half-maximal dephosphorylation. This same intermediate level of illumination causes half-suppression of the light- sensitive permeability mechanism in isolated outer segments (Brodie and Bownds. 1976. J. Gen Physiol. 68:1-11) and also induces a half-maximal decrease in their cyclic GMP content (Woodruff et al. 1977. J. Gen. Physiol. 69:667-679). The phosphorylation of components I and II is enhanced by the addition of cyclic GMP or cyclic AMP to either retinas or isolated rod outer segments maintained in the dark. Several pharmacological agents which influence cyclic GMP levels in outer segments, including calcium, cause similar effects on the phosphorylation of components I and II and outer segment permeability. Although the cyclic nucleotide-stimulated phosphorylation can be observed either in retinas or isolated rod outer segments, the light- induced dephosphorylation is observed only in intact retinas.</p></abstract><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY-NC-SA</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><preformat preformat-type="pmc-pdf-text" xml:space="preserve">
					Light-Induced Dephosphorylation of
Two Proteins in Frog Rod Outer Segments
Influence of Cyclic
Nucleotides and Calcium
ARTHUR S. POLANS, JOSEPH HERMOLIN,
and M. DERIC BOWNDS
From the Laboratory of Molecular Biology, the Department of Zoology and the Neurosciences
Training Program, University of Wisconsin, Madison, Wisconsin 53706
ABST RACT Two minor proteins of frog rod outer segments become phospho-
rylated when retinas are incubated in the dark with a2pi. The proteins, desig-
nated component I (13,000 dahons) and component II (12,000 daltons), are
dephosphorylated when retinas are illuminated. The dephosphorylation is re-
versible; the two proteins are rephosphorylated when illumination ceases. Each
outer segment contains - 10n molecules of components I and II. These remain
associated with both fragmented and intact outer segments but dissociate from
the outer segment membranes under hypoosmotic conditions. The extent of the
light-induced dephosphorylation increases with higher intensities of illumination
and is maximal with continuous illumination which bleaches 5.0 X 105 rhodop-
sin molecules/outer segment per second. Light which bleaches 5.0 * 103
rhodopsin molecules/outer segment per second causes approximately half-max-
imal dephosphorylation. This same intermediate level of illumination causes
half-suppression of the light-sensitive permeability mechanism in isolated outer
segments (Brodie and Bownds. 1976. J, Gen. Physiol. 68:1-11) and also induces
a half-maximal decrease in their cyclic GMP content (Woodruff et al. 1977.J.
Gen. Physiol. 69:667-679). The phosphorylation of components I and II is
enhanced by the addition of cyclic GMP or cyclic AMP to either retinas or
isolated rod outer segments maintained in the dark. Several pharmacological
agents which influence cyclic GMP levels in outer segments, including calcium,
cause similar effects on the phosphorylation of components I and II and outer
segment permeability. Although the cyclic nucleotide-stimulated phosphoryla-
tion can be observed either in retinas or isolated rod outer segments, the light-
induced dephosphorylation is observed only in intact retinas.
INTRODUCTION
In vertebrate rod outer segments several light-dependent reactions have been
described which may be components of the pathway(s) linking photon ab-
J. GEN.Pmcslor. 9 The Rockefeller University Press 90022-1295/79/i 1/0595/19 $1.00 595
Volume 74 November 1979 595-613
596 THE JOURNAL OF GENERAL PHYSIOLOGY 9 VOLUME 74 9 1979
sorption by rhodopsin to the permeability decrease of the plasma membrane.
Light initiates the phosphorylation of rhodopsin (Bownds et al., 1972; K~ihn
and Dryer, 1972) and activates a GTPase (Carretta and Cavaggioni, 1976;
Robinson and Hagins, 1977; Wheeler and Bitensky, 1977). 1 Bleaching rho-
dopsin also activates a cyclic GMP phosphodiesterase which lowers the level
of endogenous cyclic GMP (Keirns et al., 1975; Brodie and Bownds, 1976;
Fletcher and Chader, 1976; Orr et al., 1976; Goridis et al., 1977; Woodruffet
al., 1977). This activation occurs rapidly (Yee and Liebman, 1979). Woodruff
and Bownds (1979) recently have demonstrated in isolated outer segments
that the t
89of the cyclic GMP decrease is - 125 ms, and that bleaching one
rhodopsin molecule can lead to the loss of- 105 molecules of cyclic GMP.
The extent of the cyclic GMP decrease becomes larger as illumination is
increased over four log units of light intensity, and outer segment permeability
assayed by an in vitro technique is suppressed by this same range of light
intensity (Brodie and Bownds, 1976; Woodruff et al., 1977).
This paper reports a further reaction: the light-initiated dephosphorylation
of two proteins associated with frog rod outer segments. The phosphorylation
level of these proteins is influenced by calcium ions and cyclic nucleotides and
thus may be linked to light-induced changes in cyclic GMP and permeability
of the outer segment. It has been suggested in other systems that cyclic
nucleotides may influence ion permeability by controlling the phosphorylation
or dephosphorylation of proteins (Greengard, 1976), and that calcium ions
might be involved in such control (Rasmussen and Goodman, 1977).
In the experiments reported here frog retinas or isolated outer segments are
incubated in Ringer's solution with 32pi. Proteins then are analyzed by sodium
dodecyl sulfate gradient-polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis and autoradiog-
raphy to measure any changes in the level of protein phosphorylation which
occur in response to light or alterations in the concentrations of cyclic
nucleotides or calcium. The gradient gel technique employed in this work has
permitted clear separation of proteins in the molecular weight range from
5,000 to 250,000 daltons and is especially useful in resolving low molecular
weight proteins. The electrophoretic analysis has been performed on crude
rather than purified outer segment preparations to prevent loss of any easily
eluted proteins. The conditions employed in these experiments have been
found to maintain the functional integrity of isolated rod outer segments
(Bownds and Brodie, 1975). The levels of illumination used are those which
have been shown to affect permeability and induce cyclic GMP changes in
suspensions of isolated outer segments and are comparable to the intensities
which elicit responses from living amphibian rod cells (Fain, 1976).
MATERIALS AND METtIODS
Bullfrogs (Rana catesbemna) were kept in holding tanks 2-4 wk prior to use and fed ~
5 g of Purina Dog Chow (Ralston Purina Co., St. Louis, Mo.) with vitamin
supplements three times a week. During the holding period frogs were kept on the
photoperiod described by Woodruffand Bownds (1979). Animals were removed from
Biernbaum,M., and D. Bownds.Influenceof light and calciumon guanosine5'-triphosphate
in isolatedfrogrod outer segments.J. Gen.Physiol.In press.
PoLArqsE'rAt.. ProteinPhospho~ylationinFrogRodOuterSegments 597
the holding tanks 3-4 h before the end of the 12-h dark period and kept in the dark
1-2 h before sacrifice. All darkroom manipulations were performed at room temper-
ature and under infrared illumination using an image converter (FJW Industries,
Mount Prospect, Ill.), Animals were sacrificed and the retinas removed as described
by Woodruffet al. (1977). Retinas were gently rinsed in Ringer's solution (115 mM
NaCI, 2.5 mM KCI, 2 mM MgC12 and 10 mM HEPES [N-2-hydroxyethylpiperazine-
N'-2-enthanesuifonic acid], pH 7.5) and then transferred to the solutions described
below.
Phosphorylation in Intact Retina
Each retina was incubated in the dark in 200/~1 Ringer's solution containing ~ 1 mCi
of carrier-free 3Zp,. The time of incubation for most experiments was 8 min. (This
resulted in a stable level of 32p incorporation into components I and II [see
Results]). After incubation retinas were transferred into 300 btl Ringer's solution
without the isotope. Details of illumination, drug additions, etc. are given in Results.
Light intensity was calibrated as described by Brodie and Bownds (1976). In most
experiments retinas were agitated gently for 1-2 rain in this Ringer's solution to
detach rod outer segments. Portions (100 #1) of the suspension were precipitated by
the addition of 200/.d 10% trichloroacetic acid (TCA) in preparation for electropho-
resis. Treatment of acid-precipitated rod outer segments is described below. Other
portions (50 btl) of the rod outer segment suspension were used to determine rhodopsin
concentration by difference spectroscopy after dissolving the outer segments in 200
ptl of 0.04 M hexadecyltrimethyl ammonium chloride (Bownds et al., 1971).
In some experiments the intact retina, in 200 ~1 of Ringer's solution, was quenched
by the addition of 200/,d of TCA after exposure to differing conditions of illumination
or drug additions and then disrupted in a glass homogenizer. The resultant suspension
was centrifuged at 1,500 g for 30 min and the pellet was resuspended in 600/.d of 10
mM sodium phosphate buffer, pH 7.5. Portions (10 and 20 ~1) were solubilized in a
final concentration of 2% sodium dodecyl sulfate and heated at 100~ for 2 rain.
Protein determinations were made according to the methods of Lowry et al. (1951)
using as a standard bovine serum albumin which had been treated like the retinal
samples. The assay proved to be linear between 10 and 80 #g protein under these
procedures. Samples from the remaining retinal homogenate were prepared for
electrophoresis by centrifuging at 1,500 g for 30 min and by resuspending the pellet
to give a final protein concentration of 0.5-1.0 mg/mi in the following solubilization
solution: 0.0625 M Tris-Cl, pH 6.8, 2.3% sodium dodecyi sulfate, 5%/~-mercaptoeth-
anol, 10% glycerol, and 2% bromphenol blue. To demonstrate that no protein was
lost preferentially during the washing procedures, some of the homogenized retinal
suspension was dissolved directly into the solubilization solution and subjected to
electrophoresis.
In most of the experiments of this paper, outer segments were shaken from the
retina for electrophoretic analysis. The intact retina preparation was not used gener-
ally because the ratio of components I and II to total protein was much more variable
in this preparation than the ratio of components I and II to rhodopsin concentration
in outer segment preparations. This may have been due to greater variability in non-
outer segment proteins in the retina preparation, as well as unequal generation of
nonproteinaceous Lowry positive material in the two preparations.
Phosphorylation in Isolated Rod Outer Segments
Portions (200 p.l) of crude rod outer segment suspensions were incubated for 8-10 min
in the dark with 1 mCi of carrier-free a2Pi under various conditions and quenched
598 THE JOURNAL OF GENERAL PHYSIOLOGY 9 VOLUME 74 9 1979
with TCA as already described. Acid-precipitated outer segments then were centri-
fuged at 1,500 g for 30 rain and the pellet was washed in 300/tl Ringer's solution. The
final pellet was dissolved in solubilization solution to yield a rhodopsin concentration
of 0.5-1.0 mg/ml. Some rod outer segment samples also were dissolved directly in the
solubilization solution to demonstrate that no proteins were preferentially lost during
the washing procedure.
Sodium DodecylSulfate Gradient-PolyacrylamideGel Electrophoresis
The methods employed were derived from O'Farreli (1975) based upon the procedures
of Davis (1964), Ornstein (1964), and Laemmli (1970). The following solutions were
used:
(a) 6% acrylamide solution: 0.375 M Tris-Cl, pH 8.8, 6% total acrylamide,2 10%
glycerol, 0.2% sodium dodecyl sulfate, 0.024% TEMED (N,N,N',N'-tetramethyl-
ethylenediamine), and 0.0045% ammonium persulfate
(b) 20% acrylamide solution: 0.375 M Tris-Cl, pH 8.8, 20% total acrylamide, 25%
glycerol, 0.2% sodium dodecyl sulfate, 0.024% TEMED, and 0.0016% ammonium
persulfate
(c) stacking gel solution: 0.125 M Tris-Cl, pH 6.8, 4.5% total acrylamide, 0.2%
sodium dodecyl sulfate, 0.084% TEMED, and 0.025% ammonium persulfate
(d) electrode buffer: 0.025 M Tris, 0.192 M glycine, 0.2% sodium dodecyl sulfate,
pH 8.6.
GEL PREPARATION After degassing and addition of ammonium persulfate, 33
ml of both the 6% and 20% acrylamide solutions were mixed by a linear gradient
maker (Bio-Rad Laboratories, Richmond, Calif. or Instrumentation Specialities Co.,
Lincoln, Nebraska) and pumped (Stalprodukter peristaltic pump, Uppsala, Sweden)
from the bottom into a 28 * 14-cm slab gel apparatus (Hoefer Scientific Instruments,
San Francisco, Calif.) with 1.5-mm gel spacers. The gradient was pumped at ~ 2 ml/
min, and once prepared, the gel was overlaid with a saturated solution of isobutanol.
Complete polymerization occurred 3 h after the addition of catalyst, at which time
the gel surface was washed several times with 0.375 M Tris-Cl, pH 8.8 buffer. The gel
was allowed to stand overnight, and the stacking gel was layered no more than 3-4 h
before use to avoid diffusion of the pH gradient. The gels were run with water cooling
at constant current, using initially a 10-mA current per gel until samples entered the
stacking gel and then 17.5 mA per gel to complete the run. An average run took ~ 17
h before the tracking dye left the gel. The tracking dye was allowed to leave the gel
and the migration of dansylated cytochrome c (13,300 daltons) (Inouye, 1971) was
observed under ultraviolet irradiation during the run to determine when maximum
separation of the low molecular weight region had occurred. Molecular weight
determinations were made with reference to the mobility in polyacrylamide gel of
standards (Dunker and Rueckert, 1969): myosin (220,000 daltons), iactoperoxidase
(92,600), bovine serum albumin (62,000), ovalbumin (46,400), RNase A (15,800),
lysozyme (13,600), cytochrome c (13,300) and selected peptides of myoglobin (myo-
globin [16,900], myoglobin I - II [14,400], myoglobin I [8,100], myoglobin II [6,200]
and myoglobin III [2,500]) purchased from BDH Chemicals Ltd., Poole, England.
Gels were stained with Coomassie Brilliant Blue according to the methods of Fairbanks
et al. (1971).
AUTORADIOGRAPHV Gels were dried with a Hoefer slab gel dryer and exposed
with X-ray film (Kodak X-omat R, Eastman Kodak Co., Rochester, N.Y.). Isolated
rod outer segment samples, containing 15 ~g rhodopsin, were exposed with film for 389
2In all gel solutions, bisacrylamide is 2.66% of the total acrylamide.
POLANS
El"AL. ProteinPhospho~lationin FrogRod OuterSegments 599
d, while retinal samples, containing roughly 5-7/~g rhodopsin, were exposed for 7 d.
The film was developed (Kodak liquid X-ray developer) for 6 min, stopped in water
for 30 s, and fixed (Kodak rapid fixer) for 6 rain. Band densities from the autoradi-
ograph were determined with a Joyce-Loebel &amp; Co. microdensitometer (Gateshead-
upon-Tyne, England). The level of protein phosphorylation was determined by
integrating the area under the peaks in the autoradiograph with a Hewlett-Packard
Co., 9820 calculator (Palo Alto, Calif.) interfaced with a Numonics Corp. model 264
electonics graphic calculator (Lansdale, Pa.). Measurements were made in the range
in which optical density was linear with radioactivity.
Acrylamide, N,N'-methylenebisacrylamide, sodium dodecyl sulfate and Coomassie
Brilliant Blue R-250 were purchased from Bio-Rad Laboratories. Carrier-free a2piwas
obtained from New England Nuclear, Boston, Mass. The remaining chemicals were
purchased from either Sigma Chemical Co., St. Louis, Mo. or Mallinckrodt, Inc., St.
Louis, Mo.
RESULTS
The electrophoretic separation of proteins from a crude suspension of isolated
rod outer segments and from an intact retina is illustrated in Fig. 1. Several
proteins become radioactive when the retinas are incubated with 32pi in the
dark, and the detection of these proteins by autoradiography of the acrylamide
gels also is shown. The two low molecular weight proteins that are the subject
of this paper are designated as component I (apparent molecular weight
13,000 daltons) and component II (12,000 daltons). They are barely detectable
with Coomassie stain, but their relatively high incorporation of a2pi makes
them easily identifiable using autoradiographic procedures. Fig. 1 demon-
strates that these two proteins can be separated easily from other proteins
whether electrophoresis is performed using samples from intact retinas or
suspensions of outer segments.
Several observations suggest that components I and II are associated with
outer segments, rather than with possible contaminants. (a) In different
preparations in which 2-20% of the outer segments retain their mitochondria-
rich inner segments after detaching from the retina, the amounts of compo-
nents I and II remain proportional to the rhodopsin content. (b) Addition of
pigment epithelium, a nonretinal contaminant, does not alter the Coomassie
staining intensity or the autoradiographic intensity of these components. (c)
The ratio between rhodopsin content and components I and II remains the
same when either retina or isolated rod outer segments are analyzed. (d)
Components I and II remain associated with the rod outer segment fraction
after purification by ficoll flotation (Bownds et al., 1971). (e) In different
retinas the dephosphorylation of the two proteins has proven to be propor-
tional to the amount of rhodopsin bleached regardless of variation in contam-
inants. Immunohistochemical studies should more definitively localize com-
ponents I and II, and such work is underway.
Components I and II appear to be proteins, for they are susceptible to
protease digestion while remaining insensitive to lipases and RNases. Treat-
ment of rod outer segment samples with either trypsin (5 ~g/ml) or pronase
(5/~g/ml) for 30 min at 37~ abolishes their bands whereas similar treatments
with lipase (5 ~g/ml) or RNase (5 ~g/ml) have no effect.
600 THE JOURNAL OF GENERAL PHYSIOLOGY. VOLUME 74. 1979
An estimate, within an order of magnitude, of the number of molecules of
components I and II present per outer segment can be obtained from the
following considerations: electrophoresis of an outer segment suspension con-
taining 15 ttg rhodopsin (3.8 * 10-l~ mol) results in band intensities in the
FIGURE 1. Electrophoretic separation of proteins from isolated rod outer seg-
ments and retina. Retinas, incubated in the dark for 8 min with a2pi, either were
quenched with TCA, or the rod outer segments were detached from the retina
and subsequently treated with TCA. Proteins from the crude suspension of
isolated rod outer segments and retina prepared as described in Materials and
Methods were analyzed on a 6-20% linear gradient sodium dodecyl sulfate-
polyacrylamide gel. Samples of isolated rod outer segments contain 15 ~g of
rhodopsin, corresponding to ~ 30 pg total protein. Retinal samples contain 30
/zg total protein, corresponding to - 5 ~g rhodopsin. Protein is stained with
Coomassie Brilliant Blue, and phosphorylation of proteins is detected by auto-
radiography. Molecular weight standards are listed in Materials and Methods
and the positions of components I and II are indicated.
Coomassie stain for components I and II barely detectable by densitometry
and comparable to that observed for 0.01 pg of cytochrome c (a protein with
electrophoretic mobility similar to components I and II). The assumption then
is made that these bands contain 0.01 ttg each of component I and II (mol wt
POLANS ET AL, Protein Phosphor~lation in Frog Rod Outer Segments 601
13,000 and 12,000, or 8 * 10-13 mol is present for every 3.8 * 10-I~ mol of
rhodopsin. Since there are ~ 3 * 109 rhodopsin molecules in an outer segment,
this corresponds to approximately 106 molecules each of component I and II
per outer segment.
Both the protein staining and autoradiographic patterns of Fig. 1 indicate
bands in the retinal sample that are not present in the crude outer segment
suspension. These proteins most likely are associated with parts of the retina
other than the outer segments. Similarly, some bands seen in the protein
staining pattern from the outer segment suspension are absent in the retinal
sample. These are probably outer segment proteins present in the retinal
sample at a concentration too low for detection (see Fig. 1 legend). A detailed
comparison of the patterns is not appropriate, for differing amounts of
nonretinal contamination are found in different preparations, so that the
banding pattern shown in Fig. 1 changes slightly between experiments. It is
for this reason that attention is directed at proteins such as components I and
II, which clearly can be associated with outer segments using the criteria just
listed, and which undergo light-sensitive transformations. Work of the sort
being done by Godchaux and Zimmerman (1978), Kfihn (1978), and Paper-
master et al. (1978) is necessary to establish the list of proteins actually
associated with the outer segment.
Phosphorylation and Dephospho~ylation in Retina
Fig. 2 demonstrates that components I and II are phosphorylated to a stable
value in ~ 8 rain when retinas are incubated in the dark with 32pi and outer
segments are then detached for electrophoretic analysis. Retinas routinely
were not incubated for more than 8 rain in order to avoid possible deteriora-
tion. The level of phosphorylation obtained after 8 rain of incubation with the
isotope is relatively stable but does not reflect saturation of the phosphate
binding sites, since 32p incorporation can be enhanced or depressed by the
pharmacological perturbations discussed below.
If retinas are transferred after 8 min to Ringer's solution without the isotope,
the phosphorylation level of components I and II is maintained over the next
20 min. (The phosphorylation levels of components I and II 17 min after
transfer are, respectively, 81 _+ 12 and 106 _ 13% of the level at the end of
8 rain incubation with the isotope [mean values _ SEM for three determi-
nations]). To measure the effects of light and drug additions retinas were
incubated with the isotope for 8 min and variations involving light and drug
additions were completed within 20 rain after transferring the retinas to
Ringer's solution without the isotope. The stable level of phosphorylation for
the 20-min period following transfer does not reflect irreversibly bound 32p,
since 32p can be displaced partially within 10-20 min if the retinas are
incubated in the dark with 1 mM Pi which is not radioactive.
Light-induced loss of a2p which had been bound to components I and II in
the dark is shown in Fig. 3. (This illustrates one of the 22 separate experiments
in which the phosphorylation/dephosphorylation sequence was observed.)
Electrophoresis was performed on the outer segments from two retinas which,
after incubation with 32pi, either were kept dark or illuminated. The autora-
602 THE JOURNAL OF GENERAL PHYSIOLOGY 9 VOLUME 74 9 1979
diograph of the lower portion of a polyacrylamide gel and the densitometric
scan of the autoradiograph demonstrate the phosphorylation of components
I and II in the dark and their dephosphorylation in the light. The light-
activated phosphorylation of rhodopsin (39,000 dahons) and a fourth protein
(apparent tool wt, 12,500 dahons) also are shown. No reproducible effect of
light was found on the phosphorylation level of other proteins. A phosphoryl-
ated band migrating just beneath rhodopsin (shown in Fig. 3) can be resolved
./--.
.E 120
E
"6 IO0
ill
e
8O
IV
60
C
0
o
40
l-
Q.
0
f.
/
2otP '
o 5
9 Component Z
9 Component 11"
I i I i 1,
I0 15 20 25 30
Incubotion Time (rain)
FIGURE 2. Phosphorylation level of components I and II as a function of
incubation time. Dark-adapted retinas are incubated each in 200/d Ringer's
solution with ~ 1 mCi carrier-free 32Pi. At the times indicated, a retina is
transferred to 300 /tl Ringer's solution without the isotope and the retina is
shaken gently for 2 min. An aliquot of the outer segment suspension is used to
determine rhodopsin content and two samples are quenched with TCA. The
samples are processed for electrophoresis and autoradiography as described in
Materials and Methods, and samples containing 15/tg rhodopsin are applied to
the gels. The phosphorylation level of the retina incubated for 30 min arbitrarily
is defined as 100%, and all other values are expressed as a percent of this value.
The data are from one of three experiments with similar results.
completely from the highly radioactive rhodopsin region in the light sample
by allowing electrophoresis to continue several hours after the dansylated
cytochrome c has left the gel. It then can be shown that this phosphorylated
band does not alter its phosphate content upon illumination.
Comparisons of electrophoretic bands from isolated rod outer segment
suspensions obtained by shaking different retinas must be made cautiously,
for the protein pattern can vary from retina to retina depending on contami-
nation from non-outer segment protein. The protein band (13,500 dahons)
POLANS ET AL. ProteinPhosphotylationin FrogRod OuterSegments 603
shown in Fig. 3 which appears to dephosphorylate upon illumination can
serve as an example. The light effect is not reproducible and appears to be
due to variation in the concentration of contaminating phosphorylated protein
FIGURE 3. Dephosphorylation and phosphorylation of frog rod outer segment
proteins caused by illumination. Two retinas are incubated in the dark for 8
rain each in 200/,tl Ringer's solution with 1 mCi carrier-free 3~Pi. Each retina
then is transferred to 300 ~1 Ringer's solution without isotope. One retina is kept
dark while the other is exposed for 3 min to a light source bleaching 5 * 105
rhodopsin molecules/outer segment per second. The two retinas then are shaken
gently and simultaneously for 2 min to detach rod outer segments. Samples from
each suspension of outer segments are quenched with TCA and processed for
electrophoresis and autoradiography as described in Materials and Methods.
The autoradiograph for the lower portion of the polyacrylamide gel is shown in
the inset. Depicted is the dephosphorylation of components I (13,000 daltons)
and II (12,000 daltons) and the light-activated phosphorylation of rhodopsin
(39,000 daltons) and a fourth protein (12,500 daltons). No light-sensitive changes
in phosphorylation levels of other proteins were observed. The densitometric
scan for the dark condition has been displaced upward slightly for clarity. The
phosphorylation/dephosphorylationsequences shown here were observed in 22
separate experiments.
present in the outer segment suspensions from different retinas. This is
suggested by examination of Fig. 1 which reveals that the Coomassie staining
intensity and autoradiographic intensity of this protein band is higher in the
electrophoretic pattern obtained from intact retina than in the pattern ob-
604 THE JOURNAL OF GENERAL PHYSIOLOGY 9 VOLUME 74 9 1979
tained from outer segment suspensions, in spite of the fact that the retinal
sample that was analyzed contained less rhodopsin (fewer outer segments)
than the outer segment sample.
The magnitude of the dephosphorylation of components I and II varies
120
-- I00
80
60
40
20
!5 rhod./o.s.-s
t D
i l
i l i I t i * l i [ , i , I i I i I I I I '~
-2 0 2 4 6 8 I0 12 14 16 18 20
Time (rain)
FIGURE 4. Phosphorylation level of components I (A,A) and II (~J) as a
function of time after the end of illumination. Retinas are incubated in the dark
for 8 min each in 200 ~1 Ringer's solution containing - 1 mCi carrier-free a2Pi.
After 8 min, retinas are transferred into 300 #! Ringer's solution without the
isotope. Control retinas are kept dark while points other than those at time =
0 are exposed to 1 min of light bleaching either 5.0 * 105 rhodopsin molecules/
outer segment per second (R,A) or 5.0 * 10a rhodopsin molecules/outer segment
per second (U],A). 2 rain before quenching, retinas are shaken gently to detach
rod outer segments. Samples of the rod outer segment suspension are quenched
with TCA and processed for electrophoresis and autoradiography as described
in Materials and Methods. Points taken at time = 0 are illuminated for 1 min
at the two light intensities and then shaken gently and quenched in the light.
The data represent at least triplicate experiments for each value (mean 4-
SEM).
with the light intensity as shown in Fig. 4. Both components dephosphorylate
65% from their initial dark levels when retinas are exposed to 1 min of light
which bleaches 5.0 * 105 rhodopsin molecules/outer segment per second (i.e.,
1% of the total rhodopsin is bleached). Higher intensities which bleach 100%
of the rhodopsin do not cause further dephosphorylation (data not shown).
When retinas are exposed for 1 min to light which bleaches 5.0 * 103
POLANS ET AL. ProteinPhosphotylation in Frog Rod Outer Segments 605
rhodopsin molecules/outer segment per second (0.01% bleach), components I
and II dephosphorylate - 35% from their dark values (Fig. 4). This same level
of illumination causes half-maximal decreases in the cyclic GMP content and
permeability of isolated outer segments (Brodie and Bownds, 1976; Woodruff
et al., 1977). The remaining 35% of the 32p which cannot be displaced by
saturating illumination might represent light-insensitive phosphate binding
sites. It is known that light does not eliminate entirely the levels of either
cyclic GMP (Woodruff et al., 1977) or GTP 1in frog rod outer segments.
The two components are rephosphorylated towards their original dark
levels when retinas are maintained in the dark following illumination. Re-
phosphorylation is observed whether 0.1 or 100% of the rhodopsin molecules
have been bleached. If retinas are illuminated and the outer segments are
then detached, rephosphorylation is observed in the isolated outer segments
kept in the dark and is more rapid after smaller bleaches. Only component I
and II demonstrate the reversible phosphorylation sequence; rhodopsin and
the 12,500 dalton protein which are phosphorylated in the light do not show
significant dephosphorylation when retinas are returned to the dark. (This
point will be discussed in more detail below.)
Fig. 5 demonstrates that addition of 5 mM cyclic GMP to dark-adapted
retinas during incubation with 32pi enhances the phosphorylation level of
components I and II. No other cyclic GMP-stimulated protein phosphoryla-
tion was detected. Addition of cyclic AMP to the retina also enhances the
phosphorylation of only components I and II, and to the same extent as cyclic
GMP. (A 30,000 dalton soluble protein, found in extracts from bovine rod
outer segments and reported by Farber et al. [1979] to undergo cyclic
nucleotide-dependent phosphorylation, is not observed in these experiments
on frog material.) It is unlikely that components I and II could be subunits of
such a protein, for altering reducing conditions, which might be expected to
influence the association of protein subunits, does not alter the migration of
components I and II or of proteins in the 30,000 mol wt range. Further,
phosphorylation of the 30,000 dalton protein is not reported to be light
sensitive.)
Drugs that influence the concentration of cyclic GMP when added to
retinas during incubation with 32pi also alter the phosphorylation of compo-
nents I and II (Table I). In taking values for the dark phosphorylation of
components I and II in Ringer's solution as the control (100%), addition of
cyclic GMP to an incubating retina enhances the level of phosphoryla-
tion about twofold. EGTA [ethylene glycol-bis-(fl-aminoethyl ether) N,N'
tetraacetic acid], a calcium chelator, increases the phosphorylation of com-
ponents I and II threefold. IBMX (3-isobutyl-l-methylxanthine), a phospho-
diesterase inhibitor, increases the phosphorylation of components I and II
about sixfold. Both EGTA and IBMX have been shown to increase cyclic
GMP concentration in isolated outer segments 0Noodruffet al., 1977; Wood-
ruff and Bownds, 1979) and in the outer segment layer in retina (Cohen et al.,
1978). Addition of both IBMX and dibutyryl cyclic GMP enhances the level
of phosphorylation of components I and II about eightfold. Calcium, which
decreases the concentration of cyclic GMP in dark-adapted rod outer segments
606 THE JOURNAL OF GENERAL PHYSIOLOGY. VOLUME "]4. 1979
A
r
II I
12 13 :39 tool wl (xlO3 daltons)
B
with cyclic GMP
hout cyclic GMP
FIGURE 5
POLANSETAL. ProteinPhospho~ylationm FrogRod OuterSegments 607
(Woodruff and Bownds, 1979), also decreases the phosphorylation level of
components I and II by half when added to incubating retinas. Calcium
addition to retinas after incubation still elicits a 50% decrease in the phospho-
rylation level of components I and II. In some experiments (data not shown)
entire retinal samples were subjected to electrophoresis after incubation with
TABLE I
PHOSPHORYLATION LEVEL OF COMPONENTS I AND II
I II
Control 100% 100%
cGMP 238* 48 176* 22
EGTA 309 * 31 339 * 48
IBMX 622 * 59 587 * 81
IBMX/(BU)zcGMP 979* 90 743* 103
Ca+2 43.4 * 5.3 59.5* 8.5
Influence of pharmacological agents on the phosphorylation level of com-
ponents I and II. Retinas are incubated with ~ 1 mCi carrier-free aspifor 8
min in the dark, each in 200 /xl Ringer's solution containing either no
addition, 5 mM CaCI2, 5 mM cyclic GMP, 3 mM EGTA, 3 mM IBMX, or
3 mM IBMX and 5 mM dibutyryl cyclic GMP. After incubation, retinas
are gently agitated for 2 rain in 300/~1 Ringer's solution without the isotope
or additives. Samples are processed for electrophoresis and autoradiography
as described in Materials and Methods. Phosphorylation level for the control
retina is set at 100% and all other values are expressed as a percent of this
value. The data represent at least three experiments (mean * SEM).
a2Pi and IBMX or cyclic GMP. Only the phosphorylation of components I
and II was enhanced.
Corresponding effects of these perturbations on the permeability of isolated
outer segments (Bownds and Brodie, 1975; Brodie and Bownds, 1976) and
intact receptor cells (Lipton et al., 1977 a) have been noted, with calcium
addition apparently decreasing and EGTA and IBMX addition possibly
increasing plasma membrane permeability.
FIGURE .5. (Opposite) Cyclic GMP-stimulated phosphorylation of components
I and II. Dark-adapted retinas are incubated for 8 rain in the dark in 200/~1
Ringer's solution containing ~ 1 mCi carrier-free 32pi with or without 5 mM
cyclic GMP. At the end of the incubation period, the retinas are each transferred
to 300 #1 Ringer's solution without the isotope or cyclic GMP and gently shaken
for 2 rain. Samples from each outer segment suspension are processed for
electrophoresis and autoradiography as described in Materials and Methods.
(A) Densitometric scans from an autoradiograph of rod outer segment suspen-
sions obtained from retinas incubated with or without cyclic GMP. The solid
bar indicates the location of components I and II. (B) Amplified densitometric
scan of components I and II shown in part A. This data are from one of four
experiments with similar results. The phosphorylation increase due to addition
of cyclic GMP is calculated in Table I. The densitometric scans of samples with
cyclic GMP are displaced upwards in this figure for clarity.
608 THE JOURNAL OF GENERAL PHYSIOLOGY 9 VOLUME 74 9 1979
Phosphoo~lation m Isolated Rod Outer Segments
When crude suspensions of isolated rod outer segments are incubated with
32pi, components I and II become phosphorylated. The labelled inorganic
phosphate is incorporated into nucleoside triphosphates, 1 which presumably
serve as substrate for the phosphorylation. (The nucleotide pools remain
labelled for several minutes after outer segments are removed from 32pi.) The
level of phosphorylation is never as large as can be obtained by incubating
the retina with isotope, possibly because less 32Piis incorporated into nucleoside
triphosphates in isolated outer segments. Alternatively, the drop in cyclic
GMP concentration that occurs rapidly after detachment of outer segments
from the retina (Woodruff et al., 1977) may result in lower phosphorylation
of components I and II.
If dark-adapted rod outer segments are suspended in a Ringer's solution
containing 5 mM cyclic GMP the phosphorylation level of only components
I and II is enhanced and by approximately twofold. Addition of cyclic AMP
has a similar effect. IBMX addition increases the phosphorylation of compo-
nents I and II approximately threefold. While these findings are comparable
to those with intact retinas, neither calcium nor EGTA affect the phospho-
rylation of the components.
No light-induced dephosphorylation of components I and II is observed in
isolated rod outer segments (18 separate experiments). In an attempt to
observe a light-activated dephosphorylation, the following parameters were
considered:
(a) Higher light intensities that bleach up to 100% of the rhodopsin
molecules present failed to elicit a dephosphorylation.
(b) Supplements of 5 mM ADP, GDP, ATP, and GTP in varying combi-
nations did not influence dephosphorylation. These were added to replenish
nucleotide pools normally supplied by the inner segment.
(c) Apyrase, which hydolyzes ATP and causes partial dephosphorylation of
rhodopsin (Miller and Paulsen, 1975) had no effect on the dephosphoryla-
tion of components I and II.
(d) No effect was observed upon variation of calcium and magnesium
concentrations between 10-9 and 10-2M, which might induce any phos-
phatase activity with a divalent cation requirement (Colowick and Kaplan,
1955).
(e) Since the initial phosphorylation level was lower in isolated outer
segments incubated with a2pi a further light-induced decrease in phospho-
rylation levels might be difficult to detect. The initial level of phosphoryl-
ation therefore was increased either by the addition of 5 mM IBMX or 5
mM cyclic GMP to isolated outer segments or by using outer segments
detached from retinas incubated with Pi. No light-induced dephosphoryl-
ation was observed in these preparations.
(f) A modified Ringer's solution, which is optimal for observing both cyclic
GMP and permeability changes in vitro (Woodruff, et al., 1977), does not
influence dephosphorylation in isolated outer segments.
Thus, the dephosphorylation of components I and II is severely limited upon
PO~_ANSET AL, ProteinPhosphoo,lation in FrogRod OuterSegments 609
detachment of the outer segments from the retina and in this way is similar to
rhodopsin dephosphorylation (Miller and Paulsen, 1975). This will be dis-
cussed below.
Solubility Characteristicsof ComponentsI and H
When outer segment suspensions that have been phosphorylated in the dark
are centrifuged at 1,500 g for 1 rain, components I and II are found associated
with the pellet. This result is not dependent upon the intactness of the outer
segments, assayed by the didansyl cysteine fluorescent-staining procedure of
Yoshikami et al (1974). Components I and II remain with outer segments or
outer segment fragments through the washing procedure whether gentle
treatment (Woodruff et al., 1977) has kept more than 90% of the outer
segments intact, or whether forcing the outer segments through a syringe
needle has reduced them to fragments. Washing the outer segment suspension
in Ringer's solution containing either 3 mM EGTA, 3 mM EDTA, 5 mM
CaCI2, 1 mM dithiothreitol, or 1 mM GTP does not influence the elution of
the components. The elution of the components is not influenced by illumi-
nation of the outer segment suspensions (cf. K/.ihn, 1978).
Components I and II dissociate from outer segment membranes under
hypoosmotic conditions. If outer segments are sedimented at 1,500 g in
Ringer's solution for 1 min, and the pellet is then resuspended in Ringer's
solution diluted 20-fold with water and recentrifuged, the phosphorylated
components are found in the supernate. This supernate contains almost all of
the components originally present and only 2% of the total outer segment
membrane (i.e., 2% of the total rhodopsin originally present). Further evidence
that the components in the supernate are soluble proteins, rather than possibly
being associated with small membrane vesicles, comes from the observation
that they remain in the supernate after centrifugation at 100,000 g for 15 rain.
DISCUSSION
The experiments demonstrate a light-activated dephosphorylation of two low
molecular weight proteins of frog rod outer segments. The two proteins
(designated components I and II) are shown to undergo rephosphorylation
when illumination ceases. While the two protein components have similar
molecular weights, it is not known whether they represent different primary
sequences, or whether one forms from the other by some post-translational
modification. The phosphorylation-dephosphorylation sequence and its sen-
sitivity to drugs appear identical in both. The dark levels of phosphorylation
of the two proteins are enhanced by the addition of cyclic GMP or cyclic
AMP to retinas or isolated rod outer segments. Several observations, however,
suggest that cyclic GMP might normally regulate their level of phosphoryla-
tion. In isolated outer segments (Fletcher and Chader, 1976; Woodruff et al.,
1977) and in outer segments in the receptor layer of retina (Orr et al., 1976;
Goridis et al., 1977; Cohen et al., 1978), the level of cyclic GMP is approxi-
mately 10-fold higher than that of cyclic AMP, and in both these preparations
only cyclic GMP is light sensitive. After decreasing on illumination, cyclic
GMP levels return towards their dark values during a subsequent period in
610 THE JOURNAL OF GENERAL PHYSIOLOGY. VOLUME 74. 1979
the dark (Cohen et al., 1978; Woodruff and Bownds, 1979), and this parallels
the behavior of the phosphorylation reaction. Further, Cohen et al. (1978)
have shown that although EGTA addition to retina increases cyclic GMP
concentration, it does not significantly alter levels of cyclic AMP. EGTA
similarly enhances the level of phosphorylation of components I and II. To
resolve this issue more completely, it would be necessary to isolate the kinase
activity responsible for the phosphorylation of components I and II and
determine the effectiveness of both cyclic GMP and cyclic AMP in stimulating
the phosphorylation reaction. Farber et al. (1979) recently have isolated a
protein kinase from cattle outer segments that is activated maximally by 10-4
M cyclic GMP. This is close to the concentration found for cyclic GMP in
intact frog rod outer segments (Woodruff and Bownds, 1979). Thus, the
observed decreases in cyclic GMP would appear to be appropriate for influ-
encing the phosphorylation of components I and II.
Isolated rod outer segments are capable of phosphorylating components I
and II and responding to exogenous cyclic GMP, indicating that the kinase
activity and its control by cyclic nucleotides are maintained, at least partially,
during detachment of the rod outer segment from the retina. However, the
finding that components I and II do not dephosphorylate in isolated outer
segments might indicate a decrease or absence of a phosphatase activity. The
deficiency of a presumed phosphatase activity is not unique to components I
and II, for dephosphorylation of rhodopsin is less evident in isolated outer
segments (Miller and Paulsen, 1975) than in the living frog (Kiihn, 1974). It
is possible that the outer segment preparation is missing the phosphatase, a
factor necessary for its activity, or that the isolation procedures interfere with
a light-activation of the enzyme.
In this regard, it is relevant to note that a lesion of the permeability of outer
segments, like the dephosphorylation of components I and II, occurs rapidly
after they are detached from the retina, so that the light-suppressible perme-
ability is only 0.1-1% as large as the same permeability in living receptor cells
(Bownds and Brodie, 1975; Wormington and Cone, 1978). If the ability of
isolated outer segments to perform dephosphorylation undergoes a similar
decay, the light-induced dephosphorylation in isolated outer segments might
be only 0.1-1% of the amount observed in intact retinas. Such a small change
could not be detected with the present techniques.
Although both the light-induced permeability decrease and the dephospho-
rylation of components I and II appear to be reduced in isolated outer
segments, a light-induced decrease in cyclic GMP levels measured by Wood-
ruff and Bownds (1979) has stoiehiometry and time-course which agree fairly
closely with the permeability changes measured in living receptor cells. This
suggests that the changes in components I and II and permeability may occur
subsequent to the cyclic GMP changes in the normal sequence of events. If
this were the case, one possible sequence for steps in transduction would be:
light absorption by rhodopsin ~ activation of cyclic GMP phosphodiesterase
lowering of cyclic GMP levels ~ dephosphorylation of components I and
II ~ decrease in plasma membrane permeability. The step involving dephos-
POLANS
~rAL. ProteinPhospho~lationin FrogRod OuterSegments 611
phorylation of components I and II would be limited in isolated outer
segments.
The present data are consistent with such a relationship between cyclic
GMP levels, the phosphorylation of components I and II, and outer segment
permeability. The light-induced dephosphorylation of components I and II
upon illumination of the retina is observed over the same range of illumination
that suppresses both cyclic GMP levels and permeability in isolated outer
segments. Changes in calcium concentration, and the other pharmacological
perturbations listed in Table I, influence cyclic GMP, the phosphorylation of
components I and II, and the permeability of isolated outer segments similarly.
These same agents, at similar concentrations, were used by Lipton et al. (1977
b) on living retinas to demonstrate that conditions which increase the concen-
tration of cyclic GMP depolarized the rod membrane potential, most likely
by increasing its light-sensitive permeability.
It should be emphasized, however, that a scheme linking components I and
II directly to membrane permeability control represents only one of many
possibilities. These components might play a different role in visual transduc-
tion, perhaps regulating slower events which occur during light or dark
adaptation. It has been suggested that cyclic GMP also might participate in
these slower mechanisms (Woodruff et al., 1977). Alternatively, components
I and II might function in regulating the general metabolism of the outer
segment and be very indirectly linked to the permeability mechanism. Exper-
iments to further resolve their function would include determining the kinetics
of the dephosphorylation-rephosphorylation reaction and noting correlations
with changes in cyclic GMP and permeability during transduction. Direct
comparisons of the behavior of components I and II with data on cyclic GMP
and permeability are difficult to make at this time, because the phosphoryla-
tion of the components has been studied in retinas, whereas cyclic GMP and
permeability studies have been performed on isolated outer segments (Brodie
and Bownds, 1976; Woodruff and Bownds, 1979). Measurements of cyclic
GMP in the outer segment layer of intact retinas (see Orr et al., 1976; Cohen
et al., 1978) have not been made at comparable levels of illumination. It
would be extremely useful to measure all the reactions in the same preparation.
Experiments to localize these proteins within the outer segment may also aid
in determining their function.
We would like to thank Michael Biernbaum, Michael Woodruff, Phyllis Robinson, Bruce
Abramson, Howard Capon, and Satoru Kawamura for their advice and assistance. We also
thank Dorothy Schmid for her assistance in preparation of the manuscript.
This work was supported by grant EY00-463 from the National Eye Institute and Training
Grant GM 01874 to A. S. Polans from the National Institutes of Health.
Receivedfor publication 6 April 1979.
REFERENCES
BOWNDS,D., and A. E. BRODIE.1975.Light-sensitiveswellingofisolated frogrod outer segments
as an in vitro assayfor visual transduction and dark adaptation.J. Gen. Physiol. 66:407-425.
612 THE JOURNAL OF GENERAL PHYSIOLOGY - VOLUME 74 - 1979
BowNos, D., J. DAWES,J. MILLER,and M. STAHLMAN.1972. Phosphorylation of frog photore-
ceptor membranes induced by light. Nat. New. Biol. 237:125-127.
BOWNDS,D., A. GORDON-WALKER,A. C. GAIDE-HuGuENIN,and W. ROBINSON.1971. Character-
ization and analysis of frog photoreceptor membranes. J. Gen. Physiol. 511:225-237.
BRODIE,A. E., and D. BowNt~S. 1976. Biochemical correlates of adaptation processes in isolated
frog photoreceptor membranes.J. Gen. Physiol. 68:1-11.
CARRET~rA,A., and A. CAVAGGIOm.1976. On the metabolism of the rod outer segments. J.
Physiol. (Lond. ). 257:687-697.
COHEN,A. I., I. A. HALL,andJ. A. FERRENnELLI.1978. Calcium and cyclic nucleotide regulation
in incubated mouse retinas.J. Gen. Physiol. 71:595-611.
COLOWICK,S. P., and N. O. KAP|.AN.1955. Enzymes on phosphate metabolism. Methods Enzymol.
2 (Sect. II1):523-610.
DAvis, B.J. 1964. Disc electrophoresis. II. Method and application to human serum proteins.
Ann. N.Y. Acad. Sci. 121:404-427.
DUNKER,A. K., and R. R. RUECKERX. 1%9. Observations on molecular weight determinations
on polyacrylamide gel.J. Biol. Chem. 244:5074-5080.
FAIN,G. 1976. Sensitivity of toad rods: dependence on wavelength and background illumina-
tion.J. Physiol. (Lond.). 261:71-101.
FAIRSANKS,G., T. L. STECK,and D. F. H. WALLACH.1971. Electrophoretic analysis of the major
polypeptides of the human erythrocyte membrane. Biochemistry. 10:.2606-2617.
FAR~ER, D. B., B. M. BROWN,and R. N. LOL|.EV. 1979. Cyclic nucleotide dependent protein
kinase and the phosphorylation of endogenous proteins of retinal rod outer segments.
Biochemistry. 18:370-378.
Ft.E'rcHER, R. T., and G. J. CHAriER. 1976. Cyclic GMP: control of concentration by light in
retinal photoreceptors. Biochem. Biophys. Res. Commun. 70:.1297-1302.
GODCrIAtJX, W. and W. F. ZtMMERMAN. 1978. Protein content of intact bovine rod outer
segments. Invest. Ophthal. Vis. Res. ARVO Abstracts:127.
GORmtS, C., P. F. UReAN, and P. MANOEL. 1977. The effect of flash illumination on the
endogenous cyclic GMP content of isolated frog retinae. Exp. Eye Res. 24:171-177.
GREENGARD,P. 1976. Possible role for cyclic nucleotides and phosphorylated membrane proteins
in postsynaptic actions of neurotransmitters. Nature (Lond.). 260:.101-108.
INOUYE, M. 1971. Internal standards for molecular weight determinations of proteins by
polyacrylamide gel electrophoresis.J. Biol. Chem. 246:4834-4838.
KEtRNS,J. J., N. MIKI,M. W. BITENSKY,and M. KEIRNS. 1975. A link between rhodopsin and
disc membrane cyclic nucleotide phosphodiesterase. Action spectrum and sensitivity to
illumination. Biochemistry. 14:2760-2766.
KitHs, H. 1974. Light-dependent phosphorylation of rhodopsin in living frogs. Nature (Lond.).
250:588-590.
KiJHN, H, 1978. Light-regulated binding of rhodopsin kinase and other proteins to cattle
photoreceptor membranes. Biochemistry. 17:4389-4395.
KiJrtN, H., and W. J. DRYER. 1972. Light-dependent phosphorylation of rhodopsin by ATP.
FEBS (Fed. Eur. Biochem. Sot.) Left. 20:.1-6.
LAEMMLI, U. K. 1970. Cleavage of structural proteins during the assembly of the head of
bacteriophage T4. Nature (Lond.). 227:680-685.
LlvroN, S. A., S. E. OSTROY,and J. E. DOWLtNG.1977 a. Electrical and adaptive properties of
rod photoreceptors in Bufo marinus. I. Effects of altered extracellular Ca"2levels.J. Gen. Physiol.
7O:.747-770.
POLANSETAL. ProteinPhospho~lationin FrogRodOuterSegments 613
LWTON,S. A., H. RASMUSSEN,andJ. E. DOWLING.1977 b. Electrical and adaptive properties of
rod photoreceptors in Bufomarinus. II. Effects of cyclic nucleotides and prostaglandins.J. Gen.
Physml. 70.771--791.
LowRY, O. H., N.J. ROSEBROtSCH,A. L. FARR,and R.J. RANDALL.1951. Protein measurement
with the folin phenol reagent. J. BioL Chem. 193:265-275.
MtLL~R,J. A., and R. PAULSEN.1975. Phosphorylation and dephosphorylation of frog rod outer
segment membranes as part of the visual process.J. Biol. Chem. 250.4427-4432.
O'FARReLL, P. H. 1975. High resolution two-dimensional electrophoresis of proteins. J. Biol.
Chem. 250:.4007-4021.
O~NSTEZN,L. 1964. Disc electrophoresis-I Background and theory. Ann. N. E Acad. ScL 121:321-
349.
Ogg, H. T., O. H. Lowav, A. I. COHEN, and J. A. FERR~ND~t.U. 1976. Distribution of 3':5'-
cyclic AMP and 3':5'-cyclic GMP in rabbit retina in vivo: Selective effects of dark and light
adaptation and isehemia. Proc. Natl. Acad. ScL U.S.A. 73:4442-4445.
PAPERMASTER,D. S., B. G. SCHNEtt~ER,M. A. ZORN,and J. P. KRAEHENBUHL.1978. Immuno-
cytochemical localization of a large intrinsic membrane protein to the incisures and margins
of frog rod outer segment disks. J. Cell, BioL 78:415-425.
RASMUSSEN, H., and D. B. P. GOODMAN. 1977. Relationships between calcium and cyclic
nucleotides in cell activation. Physiol. Rev. 57:421-509.
ROBinSON, W. E., and W. A. HA~INS. 1977. A light-activated GTPase in retinal rod outer
segments. Biophys.J. 17:1%a. (Abstr.)
WHEELE~, G. L., and M. W. BITENSKY.1977. A light-activated GTPase in vertebrate photore-
ceptors: regulation of light-activated cyclic GMP phosphodiesterase. Proc. NatL Acad. Sci.
U.S.A. 74:4238-4242.
WOOI)RtIFV, M. L., and D. BOWNDS. 1979. Amplitude, kinetics, and reversibility of a light-
induced decrease in guanosine 3',5'-cyclic monophosphate in frog photoreceptor membranes.
J. Gen.Physiol. 73:629-653.
Woooauvv, M. L., D. BOWNDS,S. H. GP.EEN,J. L. MORt~tSEY,and A. SVIEDLOVSKY.1977.
Guanosine 3',5'-cyclic monophosphate and the in vitro physiology of frog photoreceptor
membranes. J. Gen. Physiol. 69:.667-679.
WORMINGTON, C. M., and R. A. CoN~. 1978. Ionic blockage of the light-regulated sodium
channels in isolated rod outer segments.J. Gen. Physwl. 71:657-681.
YE~, R., and P. A. LmBMAr~. 1979. Light-activated phosphodiesterase of rod outer segment:
Kinetics and parameters of activation and deactivation.J. Biol. Chem. 253:8902-8909.
YOSnH&lt;AML S., W. E. ROmNSON, and W. A. HAaINS. 1974. Topology of the outer segment
membranes of retinal rods and cones revealed by a fluorescent probe. Science(Wash. D.C.).
185:1176-1179.

				</preformat></body></article></pmc-articleset>
